cartserver.com 2014-02-09

# Privacy Policy | AmeriCart Shopping Cart

### Our Commitment To Privacy 

Your privacy is important to us here at Americart LLC ("Americart"). We provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. Americart, being an ecommerce service, acts as conduit for a large amount of sensitive and private data. We strive to maintain the privacy of both our merchant clients and the shoppers who patronize their online stores. It is our strict policy not to share, rent or sell such data to anyone without your electronic consent.

### The Information We Collect

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the [company name] website. On some pages, you can order products, make requests, and register to receive materials.

### Information Collection

Americart collects personally identifiable information from our users at several different points on our websites, [http://www.americart.com](http://www.americart.com/) and [http://www.cartserver.com](http://www.cartserver.com/).

If you purchase online shopping cart services, or other products or services from Americart (an "Americart Merchant"), we request personally identifiable information from you, including contact information, such as name, e-mail, and shipping address, as well as and financial information, such as credit card number and expiration date.

Americart is a shopping cart services company. Accordingly, if you are purchasing goods or services from a merchant who uses the Americart shopping cart (a "Shopper"), we collect personally identifiable information from you, including contact information, such as name, e-mail, and shipping address, as well as and financial information, such as credit card number and expiration date. Some Americart Merchants allow you to submit information about other people. For example, if you order a gift online and want it sent directly to the recipient, you will need to submit the recipient's address. In this circumstance, the types of personal information collected include name, e-mail, phone number and shipping address.

### Information Use and Ownership

If you are an Americart Merchant, we use your personally identifiable information for billing purposes, to fill your orders and to provide service to you. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this personally identifiable information to contact you. We may also use this personally identifiable information to communicate with you for several other reasons. We may use your e-mail to send you newsletters and updates ("Merchant Communications"). Americart is the sole owner of the personally identifiable information related to individuals, companies or entities purchasing services or products from us. 

If you are a Shopper, we transmit your personally identifiable information to the Americart Merchant from whom you have purchased goods or services, so that the Americart Merchant is able to collect your payment and to deliver the goods or services to you. Americart does not use personally identifiable information from Shoppers for any other purpose, except as outlined in this document. Each Americart Merchant is the sole owner of the personally identifiable information related to individuals, companies or entities purchasing services or products from it. The use of that personally identifiable information is governed by the privacy policy of that Americart Merchant. You should carefully review the privacy policy of the Americart Merchant from whom you are purchasing goods or services to determine how that merchant may use your personally identifiable information.

### Merchant Communications 

This section applies only if you are an Americart Merchant.

#### Promotional Communications

We will occasionally send you communications on products, services, special deals, promotions and news at Americart. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the "Choice and Opt-out" below.

#### Service-related Announcements

We will send you service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so, for instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance. You may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to cancel your account.

#### Customer Service

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming e-mail to verify your signup. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, to invoice you and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by e-mail, telephone or mail.

#### Shopping Cart Service

We use your personally identifiable information to provide shopping cart services. You enter information, some of which is personally identifiable information, in the Americart cart configuration form which instructs us on how to process orders you receive on your website. Such information includes the name of your website, contact information for sending orders, contact information for technical issues, shipping parameters, tax guidelines, Shopper checkout and payment options and affiliate programs.

### Information Storage and Maintenance

#### Profile

We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, and clear gifs to create a "profile" of your preferences. We tie your personally identifiable information and your purchasing history, to information in the profile, in order to provide tailored promotions and marketing offers and to improve the content of the site for you.

#### Address Verification

In charging your credit card, we may use external third party software or services to verify your address, in order to validate the charge. 

#### Modifying Personally Identifiable Information

If you are an Americart Merchant and your personally identifiable information changes, you may correct or update it by making the change on the shopping cart configuration page. Login to your account at <https://www.americart.com/login.php> and then proceed to cart configuration.

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

#### Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)

We may share aggregated demographic information about our user base with our marketing partners and advertisers. This information does not identify individual users. We do not link aggregate user data with personally identifiable information. 

#### Merchant Personally Identifiable Information

We do not share Americart Merchants' personally identifiable information with third parties. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes.

#### Shopper Personally Identifiable Information

As noted above, we transmit Shoppers' personally identifiable information to the Americart Merchant from whom you have purchased goods or services. We do not share Shoppers' personally identifiable information with third parties, except when the Shopper has provided prior electronic consent.

#### Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us.

### Choice/Opt-out

If you no longer wish to receive promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication or by e-mailing us at support@americart.com.

### Technical Methodologies

#### Log Files

As with most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information. We use Google Analytics, which uses cookies to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our site in the aggregate. Such information includes length of visit, pages visited, geographical location of visitor by IP address and other website browsing behavior. We use this information to improve our website and make it more responsive to the needs of visitors. 

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on our sites. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. We use persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file. We set a persistent cookie to store the contents of Shoppers' shopping carts so that if a Shopper closes his or her browser, the contents of the cart will be saved for a finite period of time, usually 1 hour. If you reject cookies, you may still use our sites, but you would not be able to benefit from that capability.

#### Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

For e-mail marketing communications, our third party advertising partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs). Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly in e-mails and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We use clear gifs in our HTML-based e-mails to let us know which e-mails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information.

#### Hyperlinks to Other Sites

Our websites contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Americart. Please be aware that Americart not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this website.

### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information such as a credit card number, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). You can learn more about SSL at <http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Sockets_Layer>.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### Business Transitions

In the event Americart goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via e-mail or prominent notice on our websites of any such change in ownership.

### Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by e-mail, or by means of a notice on our home page.

### Contact Us 

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: [support@americart.com](mailto:support@americart.com?subject=Privacy%20Issue).
